# Younes Hadry

Product Designer

hadryounes@gmail.com www.youneshadry.com (+212) 626 968 395

#### **About**

I am a product designer and entrepreneur based in Kénitra - Morocco, with over 7 years of experience in UX/UI frontend development. I have been collaborating with companies around the world, delivering efficient user-centered applications for web and mobile.

### **Work Experience**

Freelance Product Designer Auto-entrepreneur June 2012 - Present

I help tech startups and companies around the world to design and build modern applications for web and mobile.

Major clients:

Adobe San Francisco - USA

I worked on a branding project, alongside with the Senior Program Manager of Adobe Education.

What.digital Zurich - Switzerland

I worked on a mobile application for Adecco. My role was UX and front-end implementation for Cordova.

American Choice Modelling Portland - USA

I worked as UX/UI designer on Dashboards for clients such as Nestlé, Rogers, Target, Walmart, Canon...

Energi.life NewYork - USA

I helped the CEO to sell his startup to NBC by designing an MVP prototype in 48 hours.

Ezvid Los Angeles - USA

As a lead UX and a front-end developer, I worked on product comparison platforms such as botdb.net and inspect-it.co

Optio Interactive San Francisco - USA

As a lead UX and a frontend developer, I worked on the new version of manta.com and the new branding of Optio Interactive.

Friendryde Rabat - Morocco

As a Product Designer, I worked on an android mobile application of ride sharing, built for the Moroccan market

Stugbasen A.B / Booking Bricks Vasteras - Sweden

As a UX/UI Designer, I worked on a SAAS platform for managing rental objects in Europe.

REfindly Florida - USA

As a UX/UI Designer, I worked on a CRM SAAS and Lead Generation System for real estate.

Head of Product Pricyme / Pricemetrics August 2013 - August 2016

Pricyme is an ecommerce startup, based in Rabat - Morocco, crafting a comparison shopping tool for Morocccan and French markets. Pricyme is the company behind Pricemetrics, a SAAS B2B tool built for ecommerce stores in order to keep track of their competition and other market intelligence.

As a Co-founder & Product designer of Pricyme, I have the overall responsability to lead my team in planning and building market-innovative and user-centered products. I have also worked on the conversion optimization to boost lead conversion rate above market average (from 3% to 17%)

#### Major projects:

- Price comparison website, mobile application and chrome extension, built for the Moroccan market (pricyme.com).
- Price comparison website for French market (prixducommerce.com).
- B2B market intelligence SAAS tool for ecommerce businesses.
- Pricyme Product Manager (internal Dashboard)

Art Director Taif Design - Kénitra

June 2010 - August 2012

As an Art Director, I was leading the production and marketing teams on print and web projects.

#### Major projects:

- Official Web portal of Kenitra City.
- "Pub sur Taxi" marketing campaign.
- "Lhamza" marketing campaign.
- Landing pages of various commercial brands

**Designer** Taif Design - Kénitra

January 2010 - June 2010

Taif Design is an advertising agency based in Kénitra - Morocco. The company delivers creative advertising solutions for its clients. As a designer, I worked on branding, web design and print projects for various clients.

Webdesigner Trio Communication - Casablanca

September 2009 - December 2009

Trio Communication is an advertising agency based in Casablanca - Morocco. The company was delivering creative advertising solutions for its clients.

My main role at Trio was designing logos and executing art direction briefs into website mockups and delivering xhtml/css static code to be implemented into Joomla CMS.

#### Education

Philipps University of Marburg - Germany Faculty of mathematics & computer science

October 2014

Certification on Entrepreneurship for Academic Innovations in Information Technology - DAAD Program

National Institute of Fine Arts (INBA) - Tétouan - Morocco

2012 - 2014

Bachelor of Arts - Speciality : Design

National Institute of Fine Arts (INBA) - Tétouan - Morocco

2010 - 2012

Higher Education Diploma - Speciality: Fine Arts

## **Skill Summary**

| Software          | Web Development   | Lanuages   |
|-------------------|---|--|
| Adobe Photoshop   | HTML5   | English (Bilingual)  |
| Adobe Illustrator | CSS3 / SASS   | French (Bilingual)   |
| Sketch            | Experience in Rails front-end implementation  | Arabic (Native)  |
| Autodesk 3DS Max  | Experience in Django front-end implementation   | Spanish (Basic)  |
| Balsamiq          | GIT   | German (Basic)   |
| Invisionapp       |   |  |
| Mixpanel          |   |  |
| Google Analytics  |   |  |
|                   | Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator Sketch Autodesk 3DS Max Balsamiq Invisionapp Mixpanel | Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator CSS3 / SASS Sketch Experience in Rails front-end implementation Autodesk 3DS Max Experience in Django front-end implementation Balsamiq GIT Invisionapp Mixpanel |